A Guide to a Commonplace Book of Early American Poems
University of Virginia Library
- Poem: "A Poem", 1784 Mar 19; AMs
  [Ye sacred tomes by my inerring guide...]
- Poem: "An Epigram", 1784 Mar 19; AMs
  [Full fifty thousand Prussia's kings has ta'en...]
- Poem: "A Rebus", n.d.; AMs
  [Three fifths of the world which a wit I know says...]
- Poem: "An Enigma for the Ladies", n.d.; AMs
  [Ye blooming fair of race divine...]
- Poem: "Epigram", 1783 Mar 29; AMs
  [Says vaunting bute, `in times to come...']
- Poem: "The Power of Women, Exemplified", n.d.; AMs
  [Undone by women, faithful records tell...]
- Poem: "To a Friend on the Death of a Child", AMs
  [O why dost thou fond parent grieve...]
- Poem: "A Sonnet", 1783 Mar 30; AMs
  [Forbear, in pity, ah! Forbear to sooth...]
- Poem: "On the Two Patriotic Writers, Junius and Junius Americanus", AMs
  [See, with a like refulgent light two Juniuses appear...]
- Anecdote: "A Remarkable Instance of Sensible Repartee in a Lunatic", n.d.; AMs
- Note re: how a woman broke her arm], n.d.; AMs
- Poem: "On the Approach of Spring", 1784 Apr 24; AMs
  [Spring! Gladsome season of the year...]
- Poem: "The Miser's Dream", 1784; AMs
  [Lull'd in a pleasing sleep, old Gripus lies...]
- "Chronological Table of Remarkable Battles... March 5th 1770 to Feby 3d 1783 to Nov 21st 1783", n.d.; AMs
- Anecdote re: Dr. Franklin on hogs, n.d.; AMs
- Poem: "On the Change of Human Life", n.d.; AMs
  [Good unexpected, evil unforeseen...]
- Poem: "Ode to the Memory of Genl. Montgomery by Miss A.", n.d.; AMs
  [O spirit of the truly brave...]
- "Names of the Principal Kingdoms and States of Europe", AMs
  [includes capitals and populations]
- Poem: "The Choice", 1785 Apr 11; AMs
  [Would you, my friend, in little room express...]
- Poem: "Epitaph-Making", 1785 Apr 12; AMs
  [Sir John and Sir John's spouse the tombs survey'd...]
- 8 anecdotes, n.d.; AMs
- Anecdote: "A Pleasant Instance of the Sagacity of a Dog", n.d.; AMs
- Anecdote re: habeas corpus, [1785 Apr 14]; AMs
- Poem: "Kitchen Philosophy", 1785 Apr 15; AMs
  [In Britain's land, our author tells...]
- "Table of Interest at Six Per Cent.", 1786; AMs
- Verse: "Think bright florella, when you see...", n.d.; AMs
- "Table of Interest [at] Seven Per Cent.", 1786; AMs
- Anecdote: "Anecdote of Doctor Watts", n.d.; AMs
- "Value of One Thousand Continental Dollars...(1777-1778)", AMs
- "Scale of Depreciation...New York March 30th 1781 (1777-1778)", n.d.; AMs
- Poem: "An Irish Song. Langollee", 1788; AMs
  [My nam's Shady Carty, I don't care who knows it...]
- Poem: "Song. Heavy Hours", 1788; AMs
  [The heavy hours are almost past...]
- Note re: town meeting, 1788 Mar 19; AMs
- Poem: "Song. Guardian Angels", 1788; AMs
  "Guardian angels now protect me..."
- Verse: "The man in the moon drinks claret...", AMs
- Poem: "A Sonnet", 1788 Mar 19; AMs
  [Free from confinement and strife...]
- Poem: "Song. Conquering Hero", 1788; AMs
  [See the conquering hero comes...]
- Poem: "Song", n.d.; AMs
  [Oh! how shall I, in language weak...]
- Poem: "Song. Rouze Brother Sportsmen", 1788; AMs
  [Come, rouze brother sportsmen, the hunters all cry...]
- Poem: "Song. The Vicar and Moses", 1788; AMs
  [At the sign of the horse, old spintext, of course...]
- Poem: "A Riddle", 1788; AMs
  [I'm a hole that's too narrow when first I am try'd...]
- Poem: "Song. The Storm, or Dangers of the Sea", 1788; AMs
  [Cease rude boreas blustering railer...]
- Note re: snowstorm, n.d.; AMs
- Poem: "Song. Phillis as Her Wine...", n.d.; AMs
  [Phillis, as her wine she sipp'd in...]
- Poem: "Song", 1788 Mar 22; AMs
  [Sylvia on her arm reclining...]
- Poem: "Song. Hark! Hark! The Joy, etc.", 1788; AMs
  [Hark! Hark! The joy-inspiring horn...]
- Poem: "Song. The Pilgrim", 1788; AMs
  [In penance for past folly, a pilgrim blithe...]
- Poem: "Song. A Soldier's Song", 1788; AMs
  [How stands the glass around, for shame you take...]
- Poem: "Song. A Pastoral Ballad", 1788; AMs
  [When the trees are all bare, not a leaf...]
- Poem: "Song. The Chamber-Maid", n.d.; AMs
  [Not far from town a country squire...]
- Poem: "Song. John Anderson, My Jo", 1788; AMs
  [John Anderson, my Jo, John...]
- Poem: "Song. Sure Sally is the, etc.", n.d.; AMs
  [Sure Sally is the lovliest lass...]
- Poem: "Song. The Debtors Welcome Their Brother", n.d.; AMs
  [Welcome, welcome, brother debtor...]
- Poem: "Song. Contented I Am", 1788; AMs
  [Contented I am, and contented I'll be...]
- Verses (15): "Song. 1st" [etc.], n.d.; AMs
  ["By my sighs you may discover..."; "Ye gods, ye give to me a wife..."; "Lyle's a garden, rich in treasure..."; "In infancy our hopes and fears..."; "If o'er the cruel tyrant, love..."; "Arise, arise, great dead, for arms renown'd..."; "Through all the employments of life..."; "Fly switftly, ye minutes, till comus receive..."; "Hark! 'Tis I, your own true lover..."; "Behold, from many a hostile shore..."; "Nanny blushes when I woo her..."; " 'Tis woman that seduces all mankind..."; "Phillis, the fairest of love's foes..."; "If the heart of man is depress'd with cares..."; "The modes of the Court so common are grown..."